<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Osx on Apertoire </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://www.apertoire.net/tags/osx/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 23:23:23 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>12D78</title>
      <link>http://www.apertoire.net/12D78</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 23:23:23 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.apertoire.net/12D78</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;so, it&amp;rsquo;s been quite a while now since my last update with regards to my hackintosh, old trusted blackbeard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i have to tell you &amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s killing me the fact that sleep isnt working &amp;hellip; whenever i shutdown and come online again, i have to rearrange most of the windows in their corresponding workspace (i have 6 workspaces).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but that&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;literally&lt;/em&gt; NOTHING compared to the fact that the whole system freezes, due to some god forsaken nvidia drivers for my gtx 660ti &amp;hellip; no incantation i tried made any difference &amp;hellip; and there are plenty of reports about this even on the official apple support forums (with regards to macbook pros and such).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On March 14, 2013, Apple release 10.8.3 &amp;hellip; i&amp;rsquo;m expecting a lot from this update (since beta testers/developers were asked to specifically look for graphics upgrades).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i hope my freeze problems are a thing of the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i&amp;rsquo;m also trying to help a little with regards to the sleeping issue, by upgrading my system definition to macpro 5,1 &amp;hellip; supposedly 5,1 handle sleeping better than 3,1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;on the other hand, i was reading in zite today that 10.8.3 fixed some sleeping issues in macbook pro retinas !!! wtff !!!! (what the flying f&amp;hellip; !!!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so i have to assume the following scenarios will eventually take place&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;uL&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;upgrading to 10.8.3 fixes the nvidia driver issues. all is good&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;upgrading to 10.8.3 doesn&amp;rsquo;t fix sheet, so i&amp;rsquo;m back to square one&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;driver fixed, i have to fix sleep issues &amp;hellip; there are several alternatives to look into for the sleeping issue: applehpa.kext &amp;hellip; kill it !&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;all things considered, blackbeard is so awesome !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hotfix 1</title>
      <link>http://www.apertoire.net/hotfix-1</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2012 23:23:23 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.apertoire.net/hotfix-1</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;well, i need to add a couple of comments after my last post&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i deliberately chose to create the zfs dataset with a passphrase encryption method. as per solaris docs, this means it can&amp;rsquo;t mount it at boot time. the best practice would be a boot time prompt (a la TrueCrypt in windows), but until that time comes, i will live with loading after booting, using the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
sudo zfs mount -a
sudo zfs set share tank/backup
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;here seems to be a better way by doing zfs set key -l, but docs are scarce&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you can check whether the folder is nfs exported by doing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
showmount -e
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;if you were to run crashplan on the zfs box, i would have to think that since the folder is empty upon boot, crashplan would detect it as deleted files. i need to investigate a bit further&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;on the mac side, the disk utility method to mount the nfs export is not working correctly &amp;hellip; i resorted to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
mount_nfs zfsbox:/export/Backup /local_mountpoint
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this shows the mountpoint from the finder correctly &lt;a href=&#34;http://help.bombich.com/discussions/questions/3459-cloningcopying-to-or-from-an-nfs-share&#34;&gt;check some discussion about it here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oh solaris mio !</title>
      <link>http://www.apertoire.net/oh-solaris-mio</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2012 11:11:11 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.apertoire.net/oh-solaris-mio</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;so the plan is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build a zfs box, with a two drive mirror pool&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rsync data from blackeard (my hackintosh mac) to the zfs box&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;snaphot the zfs filesystem (full and incrementals)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;crashplan the backup to the cloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this basically gives me a two factor backup scenario: time machine-like fast access (without all the storage wasting that time machine does, on the zfs box) and offsite more secure storage (crashplan pro on the cloud)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so let&amp;rsquo;s start with my test setup&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;download &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/server-storage/solaris11/downloads/index.html&#34;&gt;Solaris 11 11/11&lt;/a&gt; (you have to create an oracle account .. shrugs)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;install Solaris on a VirtualBox VM (chose VMDK as format, since it will be easier to transfer to ESXi)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the first snag is related to NFSv4 &amp;hellip; although it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to do uid mapping, &lt;a href=&#34;http://dfusion.com.au/wiki/tiki-index.php?page=Why+NFSv4+UID+mapping+breaks+with+AUTH_UNIX&#34;&gt;it actually doesn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the first time i installed solaris i didn&amp;rsquo;t change the uid for my replica solaris user (same user as my mac box).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so i installed again, but &amp;hellip; solaris 11 won&amp;rsquo;t allow root logins, not even via console. so i did the easiest thing possible, which is to enable root logins back &lt;a href=&#34;http://candon123.blog.51cto.com/704299/712206&#34;&gt;more info here&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
root@zfsbox# rolemod -K type=normal root
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so now drop to the root shell (su - won&amp;rsquo;t work) and do
&lt;blockquote&gt;
usermod -u &amp;lt;new uid&amp;gt; username
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.unix.com/solaris/183739-changing-uid-value.html&#34;&gt;here&amp;rsquo;s a link that gave me the idea on how to do this&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;new uid&amp;gt; should be the same uid as the user in the mac box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;while on the root shell, do
&lt;blockquote&gt;
cd /home&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;chown -R &amp;lt;username&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;group&amp;gt; &amp;lt;username&amp;gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ok now solaris is installed. one of the first things i do with any new *nix box is setup public/private key ssh
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;span&gt;$ ssh-keygen -t rsa&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;$ cat ~/.ssh/id_rsa.pub | ssh user@machine &amp;ldquo;mkdir ~/.ssh; cat &amp;gt;&amp;gt; ~/.ssh/authorized_keys&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;could have use ssh-copy-id, but osx doesn&amp;rsquo;t have it by default and i&amp;rsquo;m too lazy to install it &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.commandlinefu.com/commands/view/188/copy-your-ssh-public-key-to-a-server-from-a-machine-that-doesnt-have-ssh-copy-id&#34;&gt;credits for the cat/ssh technique&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;now you have to edit /etc/ssh/sshd_config to disable password logins&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ok so we can ssh into the solaris box &amp;hellip; let&amp;rsquo;s build the backup pool&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i previously created two 51Gb virtual disks in VirtualBox, it&amp;rsquo;s time to use them
&lt;blockquote&gt;
user@zfsbox$ format
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this shows the name of the disks. now let&amp;rsquo;s create the pool
&lt;blockquote&gt;
user@zfsbox$ sudo zpool create tank mirror c3t2d0 c3t3d0
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;now the filesystem, which crashplan will back up
&lt;blockquote&gt;
user@zfsbox$ sudo zfs create -o atime=off -o mountpoint=/export/backup -o sharenfs=on -o compression=on -o encryption=aes-256-ccm tank/backup
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;by default, zfs creates the /export/backup mount point with root:root ownership. make it writable for your user
&lt;blockquote&gt;
user@zfsbox$ sudo chown -R &amp;lt;username&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;groupname&amp;gt; /export/backup
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;now, you can rsync from mac to zfs
&lt;blockquote&gt;
user@macbox$ rsync -avn &amp;ndash;progress -e ssh ~/Storage user@zfsbox:/export/backup
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you should be all set now, watching your /export/backup folder having grown with your backup data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;something else &amp;hellip; in order to watch that data through nfs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;go to disk utility, in the menu choose nfs mounts &amp;hellip; and add the nfs mountpoint, pay special attention to the advanced mount options, should be something like this
&lt;blockquote&gt;
resvport,vers=4,nolocks,locallocks,intr,soft,wsize=32768,rsize=32768
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;next up, we&amp;rsquo;ll work with the zfs snapshots, try to come up a script that automates the rsyncing and the snapshot creation and send it all up to crashplan&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>storage wars</title>
      <link>http://www.apertoire.net/storage-wars</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 23:23:23 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.apertoire.net/storage-wars</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;i&amp;rsquo;m currently running an &lt;a href=&#34;http://lime-technology.com&#34;&gt;unRaid&lt;/a&gt; server, which hosts my media collection  (movies, tv series, music, pictures and data backups)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but, i&amp;rsquo;m running out of space on the server (currently 31.69TB used out of 32.51TB available)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so i started looking for options on how to expand my capacity and decided on adding a second unRaid server, virtualizing both unRaids in an ESXi 5 head server and putting the disks on two DAS boxes (discussions at &lt;a href=&#34;http://lime-technology.com/forum/index.php?topic=14521.0&#34;&gt;two unraid servers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://lime-technology.com/forum/index.php?topic=14695.0&#34;&gt;atlas: a virtualized unraid&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.servethehome.com/sas-expanders-diy-cheap-low-cost-jbod-enclosures-raid/&#34;&gt;building a jbod das&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;at some point during that span of time, zfs came up. i researched as much as i could and finally found this enlightening thread: &lt;a href=&#34;http://forum.xbmc.org/showthread.php?tid=82811&amp;amp;amp;page=17&#34;&gt;Freenas vs unRaid&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;my take on this whole storage wars is that each solution has its merits and my plan changed slightly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;continue with the virtualized + das boxes unraid setup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add a virtualized zfs implementation to backup my osx data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the idea is that unRaid is much better suited to hold an expanding media collection, where i can add drives when needed and keep having one parity disk to protect the array. under zfs, every drive (or more precisely every vdev) would hit me with a parity space penalty&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;in my next posts, i will write down my zfs test scenario, while i wait for the parts of my all-encompassing ESXi build&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>baby steps</title>
      <link>http://www.apertoire.net/baby-steps</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2011 23:23:23 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.apertoire.net/baby-steps</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;above is a screenshot of my current setup :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s an awesome experience so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i have pretty much moved my daily operation to this machine. added two drives, one for music, the other as a staging area between my downloading machine and my unraid server (since i do some manipulation on the files i get).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;these are the apps i generally use&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;BROWSER&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;chrome is very lightweight here, and i haven&amp;rsquo;t seen it crash yet. opera is pretty good as well, firefox consumes a lot of memory and safari, i didn&amp;rsquo;t quite try&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;MUSIC&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i&amp;rsquo;m evaluating different music players&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.instinctiv.com&#34;&gt;instinctiv (free)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.audirvana.com&#34;&gt;audirvana (free)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.voxapp.didgeroo.com/&#34;&gt;vox (free)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sbooth.org/Decibel/&#34;&gt;decibel (paid)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;MOVIES&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i&amp;rsquo;ve pretty much settled on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mplayerosx.ch/&#34;&gt;MPlayer OSX Extended&lt;/a&gt; for movies&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;IMAGES&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;had to install &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.xnview.com&#34;&gt;xnview&lt;/a&gt;, didn&amp;rsquo;t quite find the same functionality in other apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;the good&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;having unix underpinnings is just huge. i&amp;rsquo;m a developer so it&amp;rsquo;s so great to be able to do unix stuff at the terminal &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iterm2.com&#34;&gt;iTerm 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;installing applications either from the mac app store or downloaded from the internet is so cool and simple&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the general awesomeness of it all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_5&#34;&gt;the bad&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;im using a pc keyboard, so i&amp;rsquo;m still getting used to the shortcuts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i haven&amp;rsquo;t found a replacement for 7zip. keka is just not there for me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_6&#34;&gt;the ugly&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;FINDER&lt;/em&gt; &amp;hellip; i find it cumbersome to use &amp;hellip; to perform simple operations i need a ton of windows open and then use some keyboard shortcuts &amp;hellip; i&amp;rsquo;ve installed &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mucommander.com&#34;&gt;muCommander&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.magicansoft.com&#34;&gt;magican file&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cocoatech.com&#34;&gt;path finder&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://totalfinder.binaryage.com/&#34;&gt;total finder&lt;/a&gt; &amp;hellip; but not decided yet what to use &amp;hellip; then there are like a ton of views in finder .. and none seems really useful to me 8)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but overall, i&amp;rsquo;m impressed and love my hackmac !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>blackbeard</title>
      <link>http://www.apertoire.net/blackbeard</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2011 23:23:23 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.apertoire.net/blackbeard</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;i&amp;rsquo;m writing this from blackbeard, my hackintosh mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i was able to build this machine and have it working flawlessy under OSX Lion, mainly due to &lt;a href=&#34;tonymacx86.blogspot.com&#34;&gt;tonymacx86&amp;rsquo;s excellent site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;two articles showed me in detail how to build the machine&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tonymacx86.blogspot.com/2011/11/building-sandy-bridge-customac-buyers.html&#34;&gt;Building a Sandy Bridge CustoMac: Buyer&amp;rsquo;s Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tonymacx86.blogspot.com/2011/10/unibeast-install-mac-os-x-lion-using.html&#34;&gt;UniBeast: Install Mac OS X Lion Using an All-In-One Bootable USB Drive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i chose the following specs for my mac:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;case: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/&#34;&gt;Corsair Obsidian 650D&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mobo: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0054OWTQU/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;amp;tag=tonymacx86com-20&#34;&gt;Gigabyte GA-Z68XP-UD3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cpu: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004EBUXHQ?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;amp;tag=tonymacx86com-20&#34;&gt;Intel Core i5-2500K&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ram: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004RFBIUU/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;amp;tag=tonymacx86com-20&#34;&gt;Corsair 1600MHZ DDR3 16GB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gpu: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004F6GJAU/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;amp;tag=tonymacx86com-20&#34;&gt;AMD Radeon HD 6850&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;power supply: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002LVUPZQ/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;amp;tag=tonymacx86com-20&#34;&gt;Corsair 650 watts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ssd: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/OCZ-Technology-Nocti-mSATA-NOC-MSATA-60G/dp/B005FYFV3W&#34;&gt;OCZ Nocti Series 60GB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hard disk: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Western-Digital-Caviar-Desktop-WD10EARS/dp/B002U1N95K/ref=sr_1_5?s=electronics&amp;amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;amp;qid=1324784170&amp;amp;amp;sr=1-5&#34;&gt;Western Digital 1TB EARS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the keyboard, mouse and display come from my previous pc rig.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;with this hardware and following the instructions on tonymacx86&amp;rsquo;s blog, i had no problem installing OSX Lion and everything is working properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to be honest, i have installed lion about 20 times, looking for the best setup possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i had two main drivers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;use the hard disk for bulk storage, that&#39;s where the data should reside&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;encrypt my system so that no prying eyes can get a hold of my data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the first objective was kind of easy to achieve, but i really struggled with the second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i&amp;rsquo;m using truecrypt in my pc, and since there&amp;rsquo;s a version published for the mac, i thought it would be a breeze to install and setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it turned out that mac support is very limited in truecrypt. there is no system encryption or full disk encryption for that matter. additionally, it&amp;rsquo;s really cumbersome the mounting of an encrypted volume under osx.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i went through several iterations of a setup with truecrypt. in the last one, i had an encrypted device partition on the hard disk, but every reboot was painful since (even with an automator script), i had to enter two passwords (the partition and my user&amp;rsquo;s).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;in the meantime, i was toying around with filevault. at first it didnt work because it needs a recovery hd partition, which isnt created during install on a hackintosh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i managed to manually create a recovery hd and got to turn on filevault, but then it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t boot (something to do with a real mac&amp;rsquo;s firmware not being present).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so i was almost contemplating a life of two-password-insert-on-reboot, until i came around &lt;a href=&#34;https://agilebits.com/knox&#34;&gt;AgileBits Knox&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i installed it, toyed around with it a bit &amp;hellip; and then &amp;hellip; i figured i could run filevault manually from the command line
two sites were invaluable on getting this to work:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.red-sweater.com/blog/1935/lions-whole-disk-encryption&#34;&gt;Lion&amp;rsquo;s Whole Disk Encryption&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jridgewell/Unlock&#34;&gt;Unlock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so i can&amp;rsquo;t encrypt my startup disk (ssd), but i can encrypt my hard disk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and i moved my /Users folder to the hard disk, so i don&amp;rsquo;t occupy precious ssd space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;thinks look good so far !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>why i&#39;m switching to mac osx</title>
      <link>http://www.apertoire.net/why-i-m-switching-to-mac-osx</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2011 23:23:23 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.apertoire.net/why-i-m-switching-to-mac-osx</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;i&amp;rsquo;ve always used a microsoft windows operating system. up until now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;today i&amp;rsquo;m embarking on the most fundamental switch in my adult life, with regards to something i&amp;rsquo;m passionate about: computers that is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i&amp;rsquo;m mac osx (lion flavor) bound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i&amp;rsquo;ve seen what the future brings for microsoft&amp;rsquo;s desktop os and i didn&amp;rsquo;t quite like it. &lt;a href=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/br229518/&#34;&gt;windows 8&lt;/a&gt; is already a stable build and showcases quite nicely what it&amp;rsquo;s capable of doing. i&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure that by the first beta and/or the rtm version, a lot of polish will have taken place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but the thing is, i don&amp;rsquo;t like the metro ui for my desktop, i don&amp;rsquo;t think we&amp;rsquo;re there yet with a full blown immersive touch interface for the desktop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it will work on the tablet, but i&amp;rsquo;m guessing it won&amp;rsquo;t work for&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;developers&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;graphic designers&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;business it managers &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the core architecture is quite nice, pushing html5/javascript as the premier development environment. but please note that you will need to use proprietary libraries (which will only run in windows 8) in order to achieve the metro look, not quite portable you see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;in a future post i will share my vision of application architecture, an open architecture, that is. one that doesn&amp;rsquo;t tie down you to an operating system and makes concurrency much more elegant and simpler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;my future reads osx. and in the coming days, i will attempt to chronicle my journey into the lion&amp;rsquo;s den.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(photo courtesy of  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/nhimproduction/6091117488/&#34;&gt;Nhím&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>